hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is jared
mikerkowski if we haven't met yet i help
coaches trainers consultants authors get
more clients make more money make six
figures and even seven figures in their
businesses today i have a special guest
her name is angie rohrer
i hope i said that right um and she has
started an an apostolic center out and
where is that that you started that at
roanoke virginia roanoke virginia as
well she is a coach and helps people
that
want to go make change in the world
positive change in the world but as well
as work with people that have dealt with
trauma and have dealt with specifically
with narcissists whether it be in their
corporate environment relationships
friends family things like that and so
welcome to the podcast angie how are you
doing today i'm doing fantastic i am
thrilled to be here it's an honor and
pleasure to be here with you today
that's awesome and we and we've done a
little bit of coaching as well together
on on your business too
um in the past that's why i wanted to
invite you i've been kind of going
through some of the different people
that i've worked with closely have them
on the podcast here just to share their
message and so tell me a little bit
about what you guys are doing uh in
virginia right now
um well specifically in virginia i did
just release the hub as you said it's
southwest hub virginia and we're really
looking at this is not church as usual
with this is not a playground this is a
place to equip people apostolically to
understand what the true meaning is
being outside the walls in your business
in your community in your home with your
children just everywhere you go and be
that change agent that we're meant to be
that's awesome and do it all over the
world change regions and and change
nations that's awesome now
you mentioned when you when you work
with people and and
this podcast we have a lot of coaches a
lot of trainers a lot of consultants
um
many people
deal with and have dealt with trauma
and and and it might not be
always
physical it can be mental and that's
what especially we're going to talk
about gaslighting
especially if you've been in a corporate
environment or with friends or people
but another thing is is when you're
coaching
sometimes clients
can be the most toxic absolutely
can be the narcissist and and as well
something that we need to be careful of
as coaches is is that we're
as well not stepping into what's called
narcissistic
monologuing when we're coaching people
so those are two things that i think i'd
love to explore
is is kind of
that as well as what's the difference
between healthy self-esteem
thinking highly of yourself and where
where is that line where does that drawn
i think that's going to help a lot of
the coaches that listen to this and
answer some of the questions that they
have from somebody that has
researched it lived it knows the answers
and so tell me a little bit about why
you
got into that why you you've
you focused on that what got you
interested in this area of
what you do well as a breakthrough
strategist uh working with people in
business not just you know with ministry
but working with people in business i
could see a lot of them that were
dealing with narcissists whether it was
in their personal life or in their
businesses
and not just that i personally have a
lot of experience of experiential
knowledge because i came from an abusive
marriage of 30 years and so the the
process of healing you know you get
married i got a psychology degree
unfortunately but the process i walked
through
it was very difficult but what i learned
was beautiful and i want to help others
because nobody was there to tell me what
i didn't know
and i didn't know to ask
so that's that's one of the reasons i'm
so passionate and why i now i am i call
myself a trauma-informed breakthrough
strategist because that's really we got
to know what where where the roots are
are there's some drama that's in us
could you give an example of that as far
as like
a situation that somebody might deal
with and how they
will
find that breakthrough if they work with
you
well an example of that is we have a
tendency to be very unaware of ourselves
we may be invalidating our emotions
causing ourselves to self-sabotage we'll
start stop we will constantly beat
ourselves up and we won't understand and
then we'll beat ourselves up and and
more and what i do is i'll take clients
to where they can shift their mindset
and start validating themselves and
learn how to allow themselves to feel
the emotion not beat themselves up and
then it motivates them to keep moving
forward so they stop self sabotaging
they stop the stop start thing and they
learn real practical daily skills that
bring them to be able to have the
success in their business make the money
they want and live the life of their
dreams
what would you say is the like the root
like
obviously
they know what they need to do most of
them in their business why are they
self-sabotaging like is it just that
they're just not motivated enough
they're not good enough or what is it
no and you know that's that's the thing
is i used to think for years that i had
a motivation and procrastination issue
and most of the time were like stop
procrastinating the thing is is people
that procrastinate 99.99
of them want to stop and what i learned
in my in my
education and and from experiencing it
myself is that i had trauma that
subconsciously was causing these
self-limiting situations
and it's just like when you learn to
drive a call a car jeremiah the first
thing you do is you're checking your
mirrors you're kind of tense you're
looking around you but eventually you
get to where you drive home and you're
like
i don't even remember how i got home
because it becomes automatic and 90
percent of what we do comes from our
automatic
subconscious so we have to become aware
of those triggers
and then we can be and then we can start
to rewire our brain to change it okay
and so where does that what does that
have to do with as far as relationships
with
a narcissist or narcissism
relationship is falling personal or in
business or both
just as the for the person however they
are and they're dealing with these
issues
of self-sabotage
how does that relationship past or
present
create that self-sabotage
well for
many that are in any kind of
relationship with a narcissist it uh
with a lot of the things that come with
the gaslighting and the you know love
bombing even if it's not a romantic
relationship it still goes on even the
business world and friendships you tend
to start you tend to doubt yourself you
become a people pleaser it becomes
ingrained in you to be the people
pleaser even at your own expense because
you have something in you that wants to
be loved accepted and validated and
that's how you get it you don't think of
it like that you're not thinking
thinking i'm going to get validated by
this person but that is because there's
something in us that feels like we have
to have that external validation to me
to to be important or be loved or or
feel like we matter and so it really can
wreak havoc on you your personal lives
your your business
really all shapes and forms even i mean
i've seen a lot of that this
narcissistic abuse even in the in the
faith uh you know so yeah what are some
of the clues that somebody can look for
whether it be in their friendships or
relationships that maybe they
have that going on and they don't
realize it obviously if you're
have people pleasing behavior that can
be a clue which a lot of people think
well i'm just a kind person
i'm just a caring person no you it's
trauma actually
yeah
not that we don't want to be not kind or
not but yeah you know what i mean and so
explain some of that what are some of
those things and where's that nuance
there
of stepping into being your most
powerful self yes absolutely i love that
you said that and yes it absolutely is i
mean many times we'll find ourselves
doing things and we can do things with
the right heart motive and things with
the wrong heart motive and if you find
yourself
uh wishing you didn't say yes or feeling
like you have to or feeling guilty if
you don't say yes those are huge
indicators because you were not actually
being
dealt with that yep say same and that is
really hard because i remember many a
situation where i would set a boundary
and say no
but because of you know this computer
program and i had to rewrite the
programming every part of my being would
feel mean doing it wow
and so i i had counsel that helped me
learn to trust myself and slowly rewrote
the program but i had to learn to trust
that i was thinking right because
everything told me no you're being mean
that's it that's it and and everything
ends up telling you that you're being
like the person that abused you right oh
yes and they will be quick to tell you
that um and that's another key indicator
if the person gets upset with your
boundary or even not being available the
way
when how whatever that they want you to
then you really have to pay attention
because these people often will accuse
you of being uncaring unkind not
compassionate
selfish
and even narcissists there you go i mean
they are really good that's a key
indicator right there yes and and and
that segways into as a coach you can
have clients that do that oh my gosh
that's probably one of the worst areas
you see it because you're trying to
serve these people
and they're essentially manipulating you
to get stuff for free
robbing you
robbing your business right and getting
away with it because you said yes to
them because they
and here's the thing they recognize most
of the time if you if you're dealing
with this people that are listening to
this podcast listen i know i've dealt
with it angie and i are talking from
experience by the way we have been this
way
and and through healing
no longer
okay so i want you to understand that
those that are listening to this podcast
is that we have lived what we're talking
about that maybe you've listened to and
i've seen the comments on my social
media there are people right now on my
social media they feel like they would
be considered the worst person in the
world to say no
to not going to dinner with a family
member because they have to go to their
kids soccer game
yes and it sacrifices the family it
sacrifices the stuff like that you know
all of that and we get our priorities
whacked out because we're living out the
story of what our previous experiences
are we're living out our childhood
memories our memories with with parents
and friends and and and this ends up
creating a framework like you said a
computer programming of how we live our
life that we have to always say yes and
that we're a bad mean
horrible person
for saying no so how can somebody a
there's two questions i got for you
here's the first one
what's one of the first steps to
becoming more empowered
to to say no
to feel less mean and actually to know
that you are actually doing the right
thing when you do that and that you can
feel more courageous you're not shaking
in your boots next time you say no
what's something that people could do
well one of the first things that you
can do especially if you're talking to a
potential client is you need to actually
look at potential clients and i know
many coaches that just take anybody that
comes and that's a recipe for disaster
in the first place because i tried that
too yeah i know
you start you set yourself up for
failure because you are
looking at yourself as the server and
you are you're serving your clients but
what about them what about
whether or not they're a good fit and so
you try to be all things to all people
and you're just not capable of that
which feeds into more of the self loss
of self-esteem beating yourself up and
feeling like and then exhausting
yourself trying to be all think oh boy
have i done that exhausted myself trying
to do this not taking time off feeling
like i have to mess up i have to answer
every message right away and i can
remember years ago when i got bombarded
after doing something online and my my
my box blew up and i freaked out it
wasn't a fear of failure i had it was a
fear of success i can't possibly handle
this but that was because i didn't know
how to ban boundaries at the time this
is so good so that's one of the first
key indicators is how do you feel and a
lot of people will get trapped in i this
is just me when you're talking
and something doesn't sit right
trust your instinct
there's a reason we we had a situation
today
where literally today uh is
somebody wrote in was a was a client had
bought a previous program they were
angry because we didn't respond over the
weekend
during fourth of july i mean they were
livid yeah and then they ended up saying
that they that that because we didn't
respond they ended up catching us in a
lie trying to take advantage of people
that that sounds like gaslighting to me
it is gaslighting and that's what
they'll do they'll you know well and
culture does not help because the
culture of this entitled mentality
people think that when they want
something that you are supposed to jump
and ask how high whether it's after
hours whether it's on the weekend
whether you have an important event
whether you're even if you don't then
you must be something there must be
something wrong with you right you're a
liar
you're a liar you're a thief you're
you're just scamming
i mean i'm sure we we both have heard it
all yeah and that's that's the thing
it's like as a business owner i would
never treat another and i want to honor
and respect
their time
not only when they're on the clock and
give that to me as far as their choice
of their hours but also when they're not
because we all deserve some down time
yeah totally most people don't treat us
that way
unfortunately
we want to deliver high quality customer
service we want to help people
and and wow people with what we offer
like i think that that's a core thing
but not at the expense of our sanity
not at the expense of of jumping through
hoops just for one person
yes and so
because of that and here's a here's a
big thing i had to learn this recently
if you're gonna have a standard for one
client you need to have it for all of
them oh yes definitely and and so as
coaches sometimes in the beginning we
end up
over serving
over putting ourselves out there because
that's what we don't have done in our
everyday life to get people to like us
and under pricing if only they like me
enough then they'll buy from me right
yeah and that well that's and that's
part of that mindset that is
like me like me like me and you're
willing to just about give everything
away and some people do give everything
away
and then of course what happens is it
actually sets you up for the pitfall
that you're not going to have clients
that are going to take you serious
because
a lot of times if if somebody of merit
is looking for a good coach they're
going to look for somebody that knows
what they're doing and if your prices
are too low right no they'll think oh no
they don't really know what they're
doing
that even our price points can make a
difference
now
tell me here's the second thing i wanted
to ask you
what is the difference between because
here's the thing every every narcissist
that i've met they seem
they seem on the surface like they're
really confident yes the truth is we
know that they're actually not right and
i learned that recently they're actually
not confident they're over compensating
for their lack of it right
what is the difference between that
behavior
and
having positive self-esteem self-belief
how do you balance that with
humility
and
kindness and compassion and not because
like like i used to think that okay if i
have self-esteem
and think
that i'm a great coach and i'm an
amazing person that now i must be a
narcissist with thinking that for
whatever reason that's what i ended up
thinking and i ended up playing small
because of that can you speak to some of
the difference between that and what
i've learned is that
your your ability to coach people is
directly connected to how you perceive
yourself
yes it really is and and that playing
small is a big factor the thing is is
with a when you know a key indicator
typically that you're not a narcissist
when you start wondering if you're a
narcissist there you go but yes no and
the thing is you don't want to be yeah
you don't want to be so because the
narcissist is not going to think that
way they think the world revolves around
them even if they don't express it that
way but you can pay attention attention
to the sudden
first off you've got things like trauma
bonding if somebody is
even asking you questions about your
trauma and connecting there with you it
may not be a narcissist but pay
attention because that is a key way that
they get trauma bonded with you and then
they
they've got you hooked in and it's
almost like a drug because you feel like
this person gets you
and but it is in their la they have
terrible self-esteem they want to drag
you down
and it'll start with these these
backhanded compliments pay attention
right
they'll say something but it'll be
backhanded and then if you get upset
they'll tell you that it was just a joke
or you you don't know how to take a joke
and you're the problem when
in reality even if it's sarcasm i always
teach my clients sarcasm i love sarcasm
and but if i say something sarcastically
to somebody i don't get to decide if it
hurts their feelings or not they do
so even if i didn't mean it that way and
a lot of times sarcasm actually has
truth to it people use that all the time
as oh it was just a joke but no that's
actually what they think of you right
and so you know so there's that there's
nothing wrong with sarcasm my daughter
and i can go back and forth but we both
know and we know where the line is you
know totally and that but then when it
comes to healthy self-esteem which is
something that we all any of us that
have walked through this life and
especially
dealing with a lot of narcissists we all
especially in business or really in
anything we tend to play small because
we've been told our entire lives that
we're too much we're too emotional or
too um you know sensitive or any of
these things so we tend to play smaller
because to not play smaller means
there's something wrong because we're
being too
proud and and that gets equated to the
wrong side of pride where the right side
of pride is and unfortunately there's a
lot of insecure individuals that will
say
you are prideful when you're not when
you know who you are and you own who you
are
and you walk in that the goal is to
attract those that are supposed to
connect with you and your voice to
empower
them and the ones that don't you
actually are doing yourself that's
celebrated you're getting rid of the
trash is taking itself out is what i
always say
you know so you need to know who you are
and not play small and baby the
way you get there is to not
think less of yourself because as long
as you're thinking
you're less of yourself you won't own
who you truly are you've got to not care
what others think and i know it's easier
said than done but it is possible to
achieve and surround yourself with those
that speak life and truth and love into
you
and here's a question for you i found so
this has been in my experience in
marketing as somebody that's like
studied this
some of the behaviors that a narcissist
does because their heart is in the wrong
place
they're not necessarily and i'm going to
explain what i mean by this they're not
necessarily
the behavior is not bad but their
intention is
yeah and here's what i mean by that
when i'm making sales copy
it helps me to understand
if somebody has certain fear or a past
trauma or something to attract the right
person but the intention isn't to take
advantage of them
yeah see or if i'm giving a compliment
to somebody to make a connection
right you know that's not love bombing
now
i thought that they were the same thing
so for for years i actually avoided
giving compliments to people
i actually avoided speaking life to
people because it was used against me
for so long
okay i actually avoided connecting
around
emotionally in my sales copy and my
marketing because that was used against
me for so long
so so
speak to a little bit of like
how do you know like where is that line
drawn to where it goes into okay
and and i think that might be just
personal for people for me i just had to
realize
my heart was in the right place
and that the reason that i'm doing this
isn't to take advantage of people or to
do stuff like that um
and i've never had anybody accuse me of
that either
when i've done that
how would you kind of draw that balance
a little bit for people especially if
they're coaches they're going into
marketing because that's the thing and
they're like wow some of the behaviors
that i didn't like
now my coach is asking me to do or like
they're they they think that marketing
is manipulation or things like that how
do you draw that balance and really kind
of keep your heart pure a and b
um have confidence that what you're
doing actually isn't a harmful thing
and c i think it's getting having the
right coach teach you which i coach
people on that i coach them in the right
way to do that but can you speak to some
of that just from your perspective and
experience absolutely that is such a
good question because i see that so much
also on my own clients and even out in
the market you know all these different
marketing areas and there are people
that have
say the right things in copy they will
play on the fear right but the motive
is is not pure it's not to serve them
and help them they say the right things
to check the boxes to get the they're
actually really good at it and and they
get the people's money where and and but
then you'll see you know people may
and they may get what they want and be
okay but you'll always see people that
have you know realized that
they got my money and then they dropped
me yeah i got my product but there was
no no customer service there was and so
you'll see that and some of that
marketing can be very
ooey gooey i don't like it when people
are literally intentionally playing on
the fear right the difference is is when
you are bringing out in your copy a pain
point
you are using words that your client
your ideal customer is thinking to
themselves these are pain points these
it may even be fears but your heart
motive
isn't i just want to take their money
and get money from them so i'm going to
say whatever i have that's going to
manipulate them into hitting that add to
cart button and following through it is
i want to help you and not only that
when it comes to healthy self-esteem
it's i got what you need i can help you
i will get you there instead of being
like well maybe sort of because we've
got to know what we bring to the table
in order to be able to take our clients
there as well
i you know i had a lady i was talking to
the other day this is a great example
from what you just said
i tried to tell her like you need to
have the confidence and believe that
what you offer is the best solution and
she was like i could tell it was
something related to trauma and she was
very offended by the fact that i said
that she was like well honestly like i
would be lying to say that i'm really
good at what i do
because there's other people better than
me and so i tell people i'm one of the
maybe good people and i feel like i'm
dishonest for thinking that i'm good
what would you say to somebody who's a
coach or somebody that that that that
thinks that way that is dealing with
their their their fearing that if
they're confident in their marketing
that they're that they're going to be
dishonest
well
first and foremost what i would say is
there are a lot of people out there
doing the same same thing in these
industries that we all work in and they
all have their qualifications and
they're good and you know sometimes
these people look good on on paper and
on websites and in videos but you don't
really know them as a person so you can
only qualify that so far by by based on
what you've seen but here is a factor
that every single person needs to
understand
they're not you
right
i come look i'm not everybody's cup of
tea and i'm okay with that exactly you
know i raise up other coaches that they
may connect with somebody in a way that
i don't that's the point so you have to
remember you are good at what you do
you're great at what you do you are an
expert in what you do and your voice
your way of doing things your
experiential knowledge as well that got
you there is going to be different we
have similar experiences but we have
also have other experiences i you know
that are not so you're going to connect
with people based on some of those that
i wouldn't and vice versa remember who
you are is what makes you the expert
because not everybody you're you just
want the those that are called you can
you must believe that you bring value to
the table
i think this is really good i think you
know to sum this up it's like we've been
talking about okay how do you qualify
your prospect
how do you talk with them in the right
way how do you avoid people that you
don't want to work with
and and really if you're in business
those are things that you need to do or
you're gonna get eaten alive it's gonna
take up all your time and energy
just trying to validate yourself
based on your trauma and some people
they need to get some help around that
you know me i worked with a therapist
that helped me what are some of the ways
that you know that people can get help
around some of those different trauma
that they have and what are some of the
ways that maybe they can even work with
you as well absolutely and and that's
the key uh coaches especially
trauma-informed coaches that have been
through it like you and i
are a huge factor uh therapists uh
there's times that if i see an issue in
a client that although i can and will
help that client there may be something
going on that i will recommend you
probably should talk to a therapist
because i'm not a licensed therapist and
i know my lane
i think you need both yeah you need
because i've been i've therapy
coaches coaches have been such a value
in my life and even people that are
close to me in accountability i had to
learn as did you to not only set
boundaries on others to have a healthy
business and a healthy mental state for
myself to be to enjoy life but i had to
put boundaries on myself
and keep my promises and my boundaries
and start teaching my brain it could
trust me to follow through when i say so
if i say i'm not gonna answer emails on
the weekend then i'm not going to answer
emails on the weekend and i'm going to
value the fact that i am giving myself
permission to enjoy the time off and not
feel like i always have to be on
yeah so that's that's powerful i love
that
where can people find more information
on what on what you do and what you
offer
well you can find me on my website and
that's angie roars like a lion r-o-a-r-s
dot-com
and there's lots of different things you
can see there um various aspects from
business uh coaching to uh spiritual
training even relationship and
narcissistic uh teachings that i do and
of course you can find me on social
media on facebook instagram and tick
tock so and it's angie roars on uh on
tick tock you can't miss me the re my
name is roar but it's not spelled like a
lion but i'm pretty loud and tenacious
so i just there you go
i love it this is awesome thank you for
being here and listen
if this has helped you those that are
listening to this podcast share this
episode with somebody
this is a message that i think needs to
get out to as many people as possible
especially if they're coaches or even if
they're not just how to know how to set
boundaries how to be confident how to be
a powerful person yet still walk with
integrity kindness
uh
being somebody that that being the
really the person that you want to be
and becoming your best self and i think
that that's really what angie's helping
people do and that's what's incredible
right here so thank you for being here i
appreciate it well thank you for having
me like i said it's been an honor and a
pleasure
all right grow your life everybody yeah
and we'll talk soon have a good one